{
    "id": "0cedb79c4dfb495ebfe3d1287a4812c9",
    "title": "Simple Past Or Present Perfect Tense",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I’m sure we ……………………… before.",
            "description": "The present perfect tense is more common with the time expressions ever, before, never, yet and already.",
            "answers": [
                "met",
                "have met",
                "had met"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t believe in ghosts. At least, I …………………………. one yet.",
            "description": "The present perfect tense is more common with the time expressions ever, before, never, yet and already.",
            "answers": [
                "didn't see",
                "haven't seen",
                "don't see"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………….. never sought anyone’s help in her life.",
            "description": "The present perfect tense is more common with the time expressions ever, before, never, yet and already.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… her once.",
            "description": "The present perfect tense is common with the time expressions once. ",
            "answers": [
                "only met",
                "have only met",
                "had only met"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………….. to my parents about my plans.",
            "description": "The present perfect tense is more common with the time expressions ever, before, never, yet and already.",
            "answers": [
                "already spoke",
                "have already spoken",
                "had already spoken"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………………… the minister yesterday and he said he would help.",
            "description": "We do not use the present perfect tense with definite past time expressions like yesterday.",
            "answers": [
                "met",
                "have met",
                "was meeting"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "There ……………………………. an explosion at the castle last night.",
            "description": "Last night is a definite past time expression and we do not use the present perfect tense with past time expressions.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "My grandparents …………………………….. a lot for me when they were alive.",
            "description": "Here we are thinking about a past time and hence we use the simple past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "did",
                "have done",
                "had done"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "How long ……………………………… married to him?",
            "description": "We use the present perfect tense when we are thinking of a period of time continuing up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "are you",
                "were you",
                "have you been"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………….. in",
            "description": "We use the simple past tense to give somebody’s year or date of birth.",
            "answers": [
                "is born",
                "has born",
                "was born",
                "had born"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I can’t go to the party because I ……………………………… my leg.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect tense when we are thinking about past events together with their present results.",
            "answers": [
                "broke",
                "have broken",
                "had broken"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Who ………………………………. you this mobile phone?",
            "description": "We use the past tense when we identify the person responsible for a present situation.",
            "answers": [
                "give",
                "gave",
                "has given",
                "have given"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}